TENGOKU-DAIMAKYO
《天國大魔境》 （推動發車）
EDION
（愛電王）
Hey, is this how you spell "Man-eaters"?
「蝕人者」是這樣寫嗎？
WEE KIL MANN-EETERS
（偶們專剎蝕人者）
You're asking as if the rest of the words are spelled right.
你這樣問好像你沒有其他錯字一樣
Let me write it.
我來寫吧
CREDIT CARD LOAN - PARKING LOT
（信用卡借貸） （停車場）
Why can I never write even though I can read fine?
為什麼我會說但寫不出來啊？
I know, right?
是喔
WE KILL
（我們專殺）
There.
好了
You have to put "Man-eaters" on a new line, or it'll look bad.
「食人者」這三個字得換行 不然看起來很糟糕
How come?
怎麼說？
On my office door in Nakano,
在我中野的辦公室門口張貼的…
it looked as if I killed and ate men.
看起來像是我會殺人和吃人
I KILL MAN-EATERS
（我專殺食人者）
Then there was actually a murder in town.
然後鎮上還真出現了命案
Everyone suspected me and came storming over.
每個人都懷疑是我，紛紛找上門來
Seems to me people get blindly aggressive about stuff they don't understand.
看來大家對於不了解的事物 總是會出現盲目的攻擊性
WE KILL MAN-EATS
（我們專殺吃東西的人）
I messed up because I was talking!
因為我在講話，害我寫錯字
Now it says "Man-eats."
現在變成了「吃東西的人」
You're making it sound like it's my fault.
妳這樣講好像都是我的錯一樣
I'll rewrite it on the other side.
我翻面重寫吧
You should include the other names so it's easy to understand. Like Hiruko.
妳應該多寫幾種叫法 大家更容易理解，例如蛭子
You're the only one who calls them that!
只有你會這樣叫牠們
Mikura called them that too.
御藏也是啊
THE IMMORTAL ORDER
《不滅教團》
WE KILL MAN-EATERS, MONSTERS, MUTANT BEASTS (AND HIRUKO)
（我們專殺食人者、怪物、怪獸和蛭子）
TWO MILLION YEN EACH
（每次兩百萬日圓）
FOR BEGINNERS! INTRO TO RIVER FISHING
《初學者河釣入門》
I hope someone snaps up our offer quickly.
我希望很快有人上門
Since they call themselves an order,
既然他們自稱為教團
I thought once we got to the area, there'd be a flag or sign on an obvious building.
我還以為到了這裡就會見到大樓上 掛著顯眼的旗幟或招牌
If it's this quiet, how are we supposed to find them?
像這樣靜悄悄的，我們該如何找到他們？
I got one! Maru, the net!
我釣到一隻了，小丸，魚網
Wait a sec!
等等
What's with the mysterious face? Thinking about something?
你這個表情是怎麼回事？在想什麼嗎？
The King of Hotels?
在想旅館大亨？
No.
不是
There's an odd number of fish, and they're all different sizes.
魚的數量是奇數，而且大小不一
I was wondering how we're gonna divide them up.
我在想我們該怎麼分配呢？
What's wrong, Sis?
怎麼了，姊？
You look so good when you're quiet.
你不說話的時候看起來超帥的
But you ruin it as soon as you open your mouth.
但你一開口一切就毀了
Wait! Let me try again.
等等，再給我一次機會
-Ready. -No, it's totally different.
-好了 -不行，完全不一樣
Wait, one more try!
等等，再讓我試一次
No way, you blew your chance!
不行，你搞砸了
Hey, there's a weird pair at the end of the road.
路的盡頭有兩個奇怪的人
They're not from that group, are they?
他們不是跟那群人一夥的吧？
You should probably report it.
你最好呈報上去
Dr. Usami.
宇佐美醫生
What is it?
怎麼了？
A couple of people are loitering around with a strange sign.
有兩個人拿著奇怪的告示在街上閒晃
It says something about being able to kill Man-eaters and monsters.
上面寫著他們能夠殺死食人者和怪物
They might be roaming bodyguards.
他們可能是浪人保鏢
Bring them to me.
把他們帶過來見我
Right, of course.
好的，沒問題
Looks like we've made another catch.
看來又有大魚上鉤啦
This way, please.
這裡，請
Watch your step.
小心
STOP HUMAN EXPERIMENTS
（停止人體實驗）
FREE THE PATIENTS
（讓病人重獲自由）
This place…
這個地方…
So, we have some business with the Immortal Order.
我們有事要找不滅教團
What kind of business?
哪方面的事？
If you've come for treatment,
如果你們想來尋求治療
you shouldn't think of it as any ordinary hospital.
你們別把那裡想成是一般的醫院
I'm here to see the doctor who offers the treatment.
我是來拜訪提供治療的醫師
He's an old acquaintance of mine.
他與我是舊識
That's not Dr. Usami.
那不是宇佐美醫生
Maybe he's a new doctor.
或許他是新來的醫生吧
Are you people not from the Immortal Order?
你們不是不滅教團的人喔？
What? No!
什麼？當然不是
What?
怪了
Where'd they go?
他們跑哪裡去了？
We lost them.
我們跟丟了
-This is a waste of time. -Wait, don't go!
-真是浪費時間 -等等，別走
At least hear us out!
至少聽一下我們的心聲
Our group is opposed to the ways of the Immortal Order.
我們這個團體專門反對不滅教團的做法
We are called Liviuman.
我們是Liviuman集團
I am their leader, Mizuhashi.
我是他們的領導人，我叫水橋
We saw the sign that you made.
我們看到了你們的告示
So we brought you here to discuss it.
所以帶你們過來商量一件事
Hold on a second.
請等一下
First things first, we basically have no idea what the Immortal Order is.
我先說明一下 我們根本不知道不滅教團是做什麼的
Are they running some kind of free hospital?
他們算是在經營一家慈善醫院嗎？
It may look like a hospital,
看起來或許是一家醫院
but, please, take a look.
但是，兩位請看
It must have been about a year ago.
是一年前的事了吧
I had an injury and went to the Order for treatment.
我受了傷，因此前往教團尋求治療
But, in the end, they restrained me and amputated my leg.
但最後他們限制了我的行動 強行截肢了我的腿
Then they attached this metal leg.
然後裝上了這隻金屬腿
We thought it was one of Dr. Usami's human experiments.
我們認為這是宇佐美醫生 其中一項人體實驗
Even now, people come from all over to have their injuries cured.
即使到了現在 人們仍從各地前來尋求他們的治療
But, instead, they are subjected to the work of the devil,
但是，他們的行動卻受制於魔鬼
and their body parts are replaced with machines.
他們部分的身體被機器取代了
That's what the Immortal Order is.
不滅教團就是在做這種勾當
But since it's called an order, they must have followers
但既然他們被稱為教團，一定就會有信徒
and people who don't complain about the treatments, right?
他們不會抱怨這種治療法，對吧？
Even before the Collapse,
早在大崩壞之前
machines were used to replace body parts that had deteriorated.
就有人用機器來取代人體惡化的部位了
This led to the idea that the brain, or its memory data,
這也觸發了一種概念 將人類的大腦或記憶數據
could be transplanted into a robot's body, thus transcending mortality itself.
移植到機器人身上，從而超越生死
From an ethical viewpoint,
從倫理道德的角度來看
it wasn't possible to actually carry out anything that radical.
要做到這麼激進的程度是不可能的
But now we live in a lawless world.
但我們現在活在一個沒有法治的世界
If there are doctors willing to take their research that far,
如果有醫生願意將研究做到那種程度
then there are probably people who would happily become machines.
應該也找得到樂意成為機器的人吧
I bet you're thinking,
你們一定在想
"Why not let those who want to be involved get on with it?"
「那些想參與的人就讓他們參與啊？」
Or, "Isn't it your fault for going there without knowing what you were in for?"
或者「你自己沒搞清楚就往那裡跑 不也是你自己的錯嗎？」
I suppose that's what you think.
你們應該會這麼想吧
It's not that…
沒有啦
I understand.
我明白
You're probably wondering why I speak out against their ways.
你們很可能在納悶 為什麼我要公開反對他們的做法
But I have seen it.
但是，我親眼見過
The repulsive reality.
令人反感的真相
Behind a curtain,
在簾子後方
I saw a body completely chopped to pieces,
我見到了一個被剁得七零八碎的人體
hacked up to a point that ought to be beyond survival.
那殘破的程度根本無法存活下來
A human being kept alive by an impossible number of machines.
一個人類藉由不計其數的機器維持著生命
When it noticed my presence,
當它注意到我的存在時
it spoke to me.
它對我說話了
Let…
讓…
Let me die.
讓我死
Even more shockingly,
更令人震驚的是
that mass of machines, which has trampled on any remaining human dignity,
那些為數可觀 將人類僅存的尊嚴踐踏得體無完膚的機器
appears to be an object of worship for them.
似乎是他們歌頌的對象
So we decided to do something about it.
所以我們決定了一定要做些什麼才行
Dr. Usami has gained followers
宇佐美醫生藉由他不人道的行為 所獲得的知識
from the knowledge he has acquired with his inhumane acts.
吸引了一批追隨者
It's possible that in this era,
他們這種做法
their way of doing things will become the dominant one.
可能會成為這個時代的主流
So this guy isn't Dr. Usami?
所以這個人不是宇佐美醫生？
That's not him.
不是他
Usami is younger.
宇佐美比較年輕
Right.
是喔
We heard that the Immortal Order
我們聽說不滅教團
are transplanting parts of the Man-eaters onto human bodies.
正在移植食人者的器官到人體上
What?
什麼？
Really? So that's what they're doing.
真的嗎？他們正在做這種事喔
That's connected to what I wanted to discuss with you.
這剛好與我想跟你們商量的事有關
It seems that the Immortal Order
不滅教團似乎
is keeping a Man-eater in the basement of their building.
在他們大樓的地下室豢養食人者
What are we going to do, Sis? Shall we do it?
姊，我們該怎麼辦？該這麼做嗎？
Let's do it.
就這麼做吧
They said they'd pay us.
他們說了會付我們錢
If a Man-eater can be killed, we kill it.
食人者殺死一個算一個
People are going to get eaten if we don't.
如果我們不這麼做的話，會有人被吃掉
That much is certain.
這點是肯定的
If you say so, then I will, but…
如果妳這麼說的話，那就這樣囉，但是…
But what?
但是什麼？
You're not as coolheaded as usual.
妳不像平常那樣冷靜
You're turning into Haruki again.
妳又變成春希了
What's that supposed to mean?
這是什麼意思？
I've always been Haruki in my head.
在我的腦海裡我一直是春希
I am coolheaded.
我很冷靜
She was naked.
她沒穿衣服
No, no, stop it.
不，不行，快停下來
From Sis's point of view,
從姊姊的觀點看來
it's possible the doctor we're chasing is part of the Immortal Order,
我們正在追查的醫生 可能會是不滅教團的成員
which might bring us closer to the reason why the woman she loved died.
或許讓我們離查出她心愛女人的死因 又更進了一步
No wonder it's hard to keep cool.
難怪她很難保持冷靜
But something doesn't feel right. What is it?
但還是有些地方不太對勁 究竟是什麼呢？
I need to figure it out.
我得想辦法搞清楚
Perfect. Being squished so close, I can only think of irrelevant stuff.
太棒了，這樣擠在一起 我滿腦子都在胡思亂想
As many of you already know,
大部分的人應該都已經知道了
this morning another large building collapsed.
今早又有一棟大樓倒塌了
Day by day, the civilization that we knew is returning to the earth.
一天接著一天 我們所知的文明漸漸歸於塵土
It is useless to us now.
對現在的我們來說已經沒用了
Those of us who remain don't have the power to rebuild what is left.
那些還存活的人沒有足夠的力量重建社會
What did machines bring to humanity?
機器給人類帶來了什麼？
Tanks! Bombs!
坦克車、炸彈
Fighter planes!
轟炸機
What did we get in return for this poison? Electricity! Convenience!
這個毒藥給了我們什麼回報？電力、便利
What we are left with, as a result, is an endless winter
最終我們剩下的只有無盡的寒冬
and a mountain of debris just rotting away.
和逐漸崩塌的瓦礫堆
-Yeah! -Exactly!
-對呀 -沒錯
This kind of thing
這種東西
is not needed!
我們不需要
-Our leader! -Ms. Mizuhashi!
-我們的領導 -水橋小姐
Are you okay?
妳沒事吧？
We don't need machines.
我們不需要機器
-No machines!
-不要機器
BANK OF JAPAN NOTE TEN-THOUSAND YEN
（日本銀行紙幣） （一萬日圓）
It's getting really crazy out there.
外面變得愈來愈瘋狂了
All we can do right now is rant and rave outside their building.
我們現在只能在他們的大樓外面 咆哮和吶喊
But if we get rid of that monster, we can have a discussion on equal terms.
但如果我們除掉了怪物 我們就能夠平等對話
A discussion, huh?
平等對話嗎？
They could release that monster anytime. While they have that secret weapon,
他們隨時能夠把怪物放出來 只要他們手中還握有祕密武器
the Order is not going to listen to us.
教團就不可能聆聽我們的想法
Well, we're only being paid to kill it.
我們拿的這筆錢只包含殺了食人者
After that, you can do what you like.
之後你們想怎樣都可以
Fine. So, as for today's plans…
好，今天的計畫是…
RESTORE HUMAN RIGHTS
（恢復人權）
Stop human experiments!
停止人體實驗
FREE THE PATIENTS!!
（讓病人重獲自由）
Now, they're demonstrating against human experimentation
他們現在正在不滅教團的大樓外面
outside the Immortal Order's building.
抗議人體實驗
But it's a diversion.
但那是個調虎離山之計
We'll use it to get you to the basement through another entrance.
你們就能趁機由另一個入口進去地下室
There's no guard?
那裡沒有守衛嗎?
The guard to the basement is one of our own.
地下室的守衛是我們的人
I've heard the plan.
我聽說了這個計畫
We're counting on you.
有勞你們了
It's so bright.
好亮喔
The lights are on.
燈都亮了
They must have some serious power generators.
這裡一定有馬力很強的發電機
All that talk of life-support systems is starting to sound more credible.
他們提到過的生命維持系統 似乎愈來愈可信了
But it's weird, isn't it?
但好奇怪，對吧？
There's no sign of a Man-eater here. Not a single sound.
這裡沒有食人者的跡象，一點聲音也沒有
Sis?
姊？
I've had a weird feeling for a while.
這一陣子我一直覺得怪怪的
I think I just got what it is.
我想我知道是什麼原因了
It feels like we're being set up. Just like when we went to find the water.
我覺得我們被設計了 就像是我們去找水的那一次
What if there are no Hiruko here?
如果這裡並沒有蛭子呢？
If there were Hiruko in this basement,
如果這間地下室有蛭子的話
then why would that old guy who wanted a transplant
那位想要進行移植的老人家
go to all that trouble looking for Hiruko parts?
為何還要千辛萬苦地尋找蛭子的遺骸呢？
No, but…
也對，但是…
No, wait.
不，等等
What you're saying makes sense,
你說的很有道理
but that guy probably has never been to the Immortal Order.
但那個人應該從未去過不滅教團
It's pretty likely he was on a wild chase after some rumor.
他得到的訊息很可能只是道聽塗說
If they just wanted to lock us up in here, that plan seems way over-the-top.
如果他們只是想把我們關在這裡 似乎也過於大費周章
Why would they do all this?
他們有必要這麼做嗎？
To use us for experiments!
為了把我們當成實驗品！
If we don't escape, they'll chop us up and keep us alive like that forever!
如果我們不逃走，他們會把我們 大卸八塊，讓我們像那樣活一輩子
They could use a gas heavier than air to put us to sleep.
他們會用比空氣重的毒氣迷昏我們
Is that why we're in the basement?
所以才會把我們引入地下室嗎？
This is way too risky, Sis. Let's get outta here!
姊，這實在太冒險了，我們快點離開這裡
Wait!
等等
What is that?
那是什麼？
Is it a dormant Man-eater?
是一隻休眠的食人者？
Yeah, it's a Hiruko.
對，是蛭子
Crushed it.
粉碎它了
It's weird that I'm glad there was a Man-eater here,
還真奇怪 看到食人者竟然讓我們這麼開心
but looks like you were worried about nothing.
但看來你是多慮了
Right.
也是
Wha-- Sis!
啊…姊！
Isn't that one down there too?
那裡是不是還有一隻？
Another? What the hell?
還有一隻？搞什麼啊
I thought there was only one.
我以為只有一隻
There could be more. We need to cover every corner.
可能還有更多，我們得檢查每個角落
The fact that they're not moving
牠們一動也不動的
is actually more annoying.
反而更惹人厭
Got you.
逮到你了
Is this guy the big boss?
這隻是牠們的老大嗎？
Gross.
噁心
Did those little ones multiply from this guy?
那些小隻的是這傢伙繁殖出來的嗎？
But why are they frozen stiff?
但為什麼牠們全都硬邦邦的？
When a Man-eater is on the verge of death, it enters a state of suspended animation.
當食人者瀕臨死亡時 就會進入一種假死狀態
They survive by playing dead.
牠們藉著裝死存活下來
These ones probably haven't had any food since being trapped down here.
自從被困在這裡之後 牠們可能再也沒進食過
Right. Food…
對了，食物…
And now that two humans have shown up,
現在來了兩個人類
I guess they'll start to wake up?
我猜牠們會開始甦醒了？
There!
那裡
Sis!
姊
There's a little one that's moving!
那裡有個小隻的在移動
I don't know if I got it.
我不確定是否打中牠了
Where'd you go?
跑哪裡去了？
No.
不行
They've got quick moves. Watch out!
牠們移動的速度變快了，小心
No way.
不是吧
They're slipping through the walls.
牠們穿牆而過了
Damn it, get off!
該死，放開我
Maru, run!
小丸，快跑
Maru!
小丸
Go to hell!
去死吧
This can't be happening.
這不是真的
Die!
去死
Just die already!
給我去死吧
Let me go!
放開我
Help.
救命啊
Help me, Robin!
救救我，露敏
It's over.
結束了
I can't…
我沒辦法…
breathe.
呼吸了
You're okay.
沒事了
There's nothing here. Nothing happened!
這裡什麼都沒有，什麼事都沒發生
Was I dreaming?
我在做夢嗎？
That's impossible. Did it make me hallucinate?
不可能吧，牠會讓我產生幻覺嗎？
Thank God. You're back to reality.
感謝老天，妳回到現實了
I don't know what I'd have done if you'd stayed like that.
如果妳一直這樣下去的話 我還真不知道該怎麼辦
You just started shooting at nothing and flailing violently out of nowhere.
妳莫名其妙地 突然開始漫無目標地瘋狂掃射
Just rest like that for a bit.
妳就這樣休息一下吧
I'll deal with the rest of the Hiruko.
我來解決剩下的蛭子
Hey, Sis?
姊？
I guess you wanted Robin to save you.
我想妳希望露敏來救妳
What?
什麼？
Sorry, I thought they'd already got you.
抱歉，我以為你已經被牠們抓住了
Damn it.
該死
What kind of guy says something so stupid?
我怎麼會說出這種蠢話啊？
Why exactly should I be apologizing?
我到底在抱歉什麼啊？
I think that's all of them.
我想我們已經全都處理掉了
Are you feeling better, Sis?
妳好一點了嗎，姊？
Yeah.
好一點了
When you were staring at that huge Hiruko,
當妳凝視著那隻巨大的蛭子時
it must have hypnotized you. I'm sure of it.
牠一定把妳催眠了，我很肯定
That's why I told you you weren't as coolheaded as usual.
所以我才會說妳不如平時那樣冷靜
I'll try and focus more.
我會試著打起精神來
-Hey! -Ouch.
-喂 -好痛
As if you're trying to sneak another one in!
你難道又想偷來一次？
Are you stupid?
你是笨蛋嗎？
Someone's coming.
有人來了
Is it dead?
牠死了嗎？
Really?
真的嗎？
This guy's clearly bad news.
這傢伙一看就是個麻煩人物
There's someone else I want you to kill.
我想請你們殺了另外一個人
Someone I want you to help.
請你們救救一個人
If we can.
我們辦得到的話是可以啦
I mean, it depends on what you're asking.
不過，還是得看你要我們做什麼
Aren't you from the Immortal Order?
你不是不滅教團的人嗎？
I don't remember ever referring to it that way,
我不記得這樣稱呼過自己
but I've heard it called that before.
但我聽別人這麼說過
Right.
是喔
So, is Dr. Usami here? We want to see him.
宇佐美醫生在這裡嗎？我們想見他一面
Usami?
宇佐美？
That's me.
就是我